[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：现在是异步的时候了。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: It's time now for a Asynchronicity.
所以世界上有两种功能，
So there are two kinds of functions in the world,
有同步功能和异步功能。
there are Synchronous functions and Asynchronous functions.
因此，让我们首先看一下同步函数。
So let's first look at Synchronous functions.
同步函数是不返回的函数
A Synchronous function is a function that does not return
直到工作完成或失败。
until the work is completed or has failed.
所以我们过去几天写的所有函数都是
So all of the functions that we wrote for the last couple of days have been
同步功能，因为它们就是这样工作的。
synchronous functions because that's how they work.
这在函数中是非常有用的，因为它意味着，
And that's a very useful thing to have in a function because it means,
随着时间的推移，很容易对它的行为进行推理。
it's easy to reason about its behavior over time.
当异步函数调用另一个同步函数时。
When asynchronous function calls another synchronous function.
呼叫者被及时挂起
The caller is suspended in time and
在被呼叫者返回之前没有任何进展。
nothing advances until the the callee returns.
如果呼叫者在他们拨打电话的那一刻正在看时钟。
If the caller is looking at a clock at the moment that they make the call.
他们的经验是，双手快速向前跳跃。
Their experience will be, that the hands jump forward quickly.
但除此之外，他们并不知道这件事已经发生了，
But otherwise, they're not aware that this stuff has happened,
除了他们要求的东西已经神奇地完成了。
except that the thing that they asked for has magically been completed.
这使得我们很容易对事情进行推理，
And that makes it easy for us to reason about things,
除非我们需要让多件事情同时发生。
unless we need to make multiple things happen at the same time.
如果你在时间上被暂停，你不能让多件事情同时发生。
You can't make multiple things happen at the same time if you're suspended in time.
所以，Topham减轻的方式是通过使用线程，
So, the way that Topham mitigated is by use of the threads,
该线程允许有多个执行线程通过
that thread allows to have multiple threads of execution happening through
同时存储空间。
a memory space at the same time.
所以这是很多事情，而且同时发生。
So that's lots of things and happen at the same time.
不幸的是，比赛带来了一些问题，包括，
Unfortunately, races come with some problems including,
线程会带来一些问题，包括竞争、死锁和
threads come with problems including races, deadlocks and
其他可靠性问题和性能问题，并将更多地关注这些问题。
other reliability problems and performance problems, and will look more at these.
因此，线程模型，像所有模型一样，都有优点和缺点。
So the threading model, like all models comes with pros and cons.
而第一个专业人士是非常重要，非常重要的一个。
And the first pro is a really important, really significant one.
没有必要重新思考。
No rethinking is necessary.
您可以获取任何现有的代码片段，将其放入线程中，然后
You can take any existing piece of code, put it in a thread and
那样就行了。
it'll just work that way.
你不需要对它做任何改变，
You don't have to make any changes to it,
以便将其引入线程环境。
in order to introduce it to a threaded environment.
现在这并不一定意味着你永远不需要改变它，
Now that doesn't necessarily mean that you'll never need to change it,
但是启动阶段真的很容易。
but the starting up phase is really easy.
下一个专业是阻塞程序是好的。
The next pro is that blocking programs are okay.
程序阻塞是可以的，事实上，这就是线程的用途。
It's okay for programs to block and in fact, that is what threads are for.
线程存在，所以事情可以停止。
Threads exist, so that things can stop.
在它停止的时候还有其他的事情发生。
And have other things happening while it stopped.
只要没有阻塞任何线程，执行就会继续。
Execution will continue as long as any thread is not blocked.
但也有一些缺点。
But there are some cons.
第一个缺点是每个线程都分配了卡住的内存。
The first con is that there is stuck memory allocated per thread.
这曾经是一个重大的问题。
This used to be a significant problem.
不再是了。
It's not any more.
摩尔定律继续增加记忆容量，并且
Moore's Law continued to ramp on memory capacity, and
因此线程堆栈现在处于噪音中。
so thread stacks are now in the noise.
我们不再关心他们了。
We don't care about them anymore.
更重要的缺点是，如果两个线程在相同的时间使用相同的内存
A more important con is that if two threads use the same memory at the same
时间，一场比赛可能会发生。
time, a race may occur.
事实上，这是一个很大的问题。
And the fact, this is a big problem.
所以很多人都在问，
So a lot of people been asking,
我们什么时候才能在JavaScript中获得线程，答案是永远不会。
when are we going get threads in JavaScript and the answer is never.
让我来解释一下原因。
And let me illustrate why.
所以在这里我们有两个程序，每个程序都将在自己的线程中运行
So here we have two programs which will each run in its own thread and
我们在运行它们，可能是在同一时间。
we were run them, possibly at the same time.
这个计划有很多可能的后果。
And there are a number of possible consequences of this program.
一个是包含A和B的数组。
One is, an array containing A and B.
另一个是包含B和A的数组。
And the other is, an array containing B and A.
因为我们可以控制这两个线程运行的顺序，
Because we can control in what order these two threads run,
这是两种可能的结果。
these are two possible outcomes.
但我担心的不是这场比赛，我担心的是这场比赛。
But that's not the race I'm worried about, the race I'm worried about is this one.
这个程序的另一个可能的结果是一个只包含OR的数组
Another possible outcome of this program is an array containing only a or
仅包含b的数组。
an array containing only b.
这不是因为什么
And this is not due to anything,
除了这两个语句中发生的情况之外，您可以查看这些
except what's happening in these two statements, and you can look at these for
很长一段时间，并试图找出我的一半数据去了。
a long time and try to figure out did half of my data go.
这怎么会失败呢？
How did this fail?
很难对线程中的程序进行推理。
It's really hard to reason about programs that race in threads.
所以让我们放大这个，看看发生了什么。
So let's zoom in on this and look at what's going on.
这是第一句话
So that's the first statement.
使工作具有描述性和
One of the things that makes jobs descriptive and
表达能力强大的语言是一种语句可以做的工作
expressively powerful language is that one statement can do the work of
很多声明，就是这样，
many statements and that's the case,
在这一条中，顶部的一条语句做了四条绿线所做的事情。
in this one, that one statement on the top, does what the four green lines do.
它将获得我们将分配给数组部分的当前长度。
It'll get the current length that we'll assign to the part of the array.
如果数组的长度增加了，那么我们将进行更改。
If the length of the array has increased, then we'll make that change.
如果我们看第二个线程，它也会扩展成类似的东西。
And if we look at the second thread, it also expands into stuff like that.
并且我们不能控制这些在实际执行中可能如何排序。
And we cannot control how these might be ordered in actual execution.
所以一种可能的订购方式是
So one possible ordering could be
两者同时捕获长度，并且都将使用该长度
both capture the length at the same time, and both will be using that
为了存储到RAIN中，两者都将使用它来更改数组的长度。
to store into the rain both will be using it to change the length of the arrays.
因此，无论哪一秒跑都可能会赢。
And as a result, which ever one run second is probably going to win.
这就是我们一半的数据去了哪里。
So that's where half of our data went.
这些东西真的很难推理。
And this stuff is really hard to reason about.
首先，你不能在原始代码中看到它，但它比这个更糟糕，
For one thing, you can't see it in the original code but it's worse than this,
因为这些语句中的每一个都可以扩展为多个机器语言
because each of these statements could expand into multiple machine language
声明。
statements.
你不知道这些将如何交错。
And you don't know how those are gonna interleave.
每一个都可以在低层次扩展成微指令
And each of those could expand at the low level into micro instructions and
你不能控制这些交错的方式，可能就是这样
you can't control how those will interleave and it may be that
此线程代码的实时行为随加载而变化。
the real time behavior of this threaded code changes according to loading.
所以在开发过程中可能工作得很好，但是
So might be working fine during development, but
当我们投入生产时就失败了。
then fail when we put in production.
或者它在一年中的大部分时间都工作得很好，但在圣诞节时却失败了。
Or it's working fine most of the year, but it fails at Christmas.
随着事物的变化，那些看起来不会影响行为的事物
As things change, things that wouldn't appear to affect the behavior of
程序实际上可以从根本上影响程序的行为。
the program can actually radically affect the behavior of the program.
所以不可能有应用程序完整性，
So it's impossible to have application integrity,
当我们受到比赛条件的影响时。
when we're subject to race conditions.
这样我们就可以通过相互排斥来缓解这种情况。
So that we mitigate that with mutual exclusion.
互斥只允许一个
Mutual exclusion allows only one
线程一次在存储器的临界区中运行，
thread to be running in a critical section of memory at a time,
这种东西有很长的历史，从Dykstra信号量开始。
and there's a long history of this stuff, starting with Dykstra semaphores.
或者当一匹马监视着编辑的约会，
Or as an horse monitors the editor rendezvousing,
现在我们捕捉到了同步，但这些都是基于相同想法的转换。
now we caught synchronization but these are all transforms on the same idea.
这曾经是操作系统的东西。
This used to be operating system stuff.
过去只有操作系统涉及互斥和
Used to be only operating systems were concerned with mutual exclusion and
同时运行多个东西，但这些都渗入了应用程序，
running multiple things at the same time, but this has all leaked into applications,
因为网络和多核问题。
because of networking and because of the multi-core problem.
与网络有关的问题是，&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：我们希望
The concern with networking is that, &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: We want
能够让事情发生，而缓慢的事情正在发生。
to be able to have stuff happening while slow things are happening.
我们能做的最慢的事情之一就是进入网络，
And one of the slowest things we can do is go out to the network,
因为它有很大的延迟，并且
cuz that has a large latencies, and
在某些情况下是高贵的潜伏期，所以你可以被停止很长一段时间
In some cases are noble latencies, and so you can be stopped for a long time and
一般来说，你不能让系统挂起那么长时间。
generally, you can't afford to have systems be suspended for that long.
所以你需要线程才能让它们继续。
So you need threads in order to allow them to continue.
然后是多核问题，
Then there is the multi-core problem,
CPU设计者已经失去了让CPU运行得更快的能力。
CPU designers have lost the ability to make CPU's go faster.
所以相反，他们给了我们更多。
So instead, they're giving us more of them.
我们不知道如何使用它们，除非你有问题
And we don't know how to use them, unless if you have a problem that's
令人尴尬的平行，然后我们可以利用它。
embarrassingly parallel, then we can take advantage of it.
但我们所做的大多数事情都是令人尴尬的连续不断
But most of what we do is embarrassingly serial and
我们不知道如何将多个内核放入我们的应用程序中
we don't know how to take multiple cores and put them in our applications and
从中获得显著的好处。
get a significant benefit from it.
所以这就是我们所在的地方。
So that's where we are.
所以在相互排斥的情况下，
So with mutual exclusion,
一次只能在临界区中执行一个线程，并且
only one thread can be executing in a critical section at a time and
在临界区中等待执行的所有其他线程都将被阻止。
all other threads waiting to execute in the critical section will be blocked.
如果线程不相互作用，
If the threads don't interact,
然后程序可以在所有核心上全速运行。
then the programs can run at full speed across all the cores.
但如果它们确实相互作用，那么除非采用互斥，否则就会出现种族。
But if they do interact, then races will occur unless mutual exclusion is employed.
不幸的是，相互排斥也有其阴暗面。
Unfortunately, mutual exclusion comes with its own dark side.
这就是僵局。
And that is deadlock.
这里我们有两个线程，Alphonse和Gaston。
Here we have two threads, Alphonse and Gaston.
它们都是等待的程序
They are both program to wait for
另一个要站起来，才能站起来。
the other to stand up, before they can stand up.
这是僵局。
This is deadlock.
事实证明，计算机系统一直都在这样做。
It turns out computer systems do this all the time.
这是另一个例子。
Here's another example.
这是圣保罗的一个真实世界的例子。
This is a real world example from Sao Paulo.
你可以想到，显然他们一直在这样做。
You can think of, apparently they do this all the time.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯·克罗克福德：你可以想到
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: You can think of
这些车中的每一辆都是一条线，随时可以运行。
each of these cars as being a thread, which is ready to run.
它只是在等待阻塞它的线程让路。
It's just waiting for the thread that's blocking it to get out of the way.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[laugh]&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：所以死锁，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: So deadlock,
这是件严肃的事。
it's a serious thing.